and so on.
So let me continue.
On the RS feed thing, basically it's an
RS feed that constantly changes, right?
So depending on how people publish the application,
for example, if I pull from that RS feed today, I get the
latest five articles, but in one week, the latest five
articles are different, right? Because they're
always the latest. So like this, you can pull information
from all kinds of sources, very easily. But anyway,
this is the input, basically a bunch of URLs,
static or moving, depending on the type
of thread. And then on the architectural side,
this is what happens. So we have first an orchestrator
that gets as input all these URLs. And
depending on the platform, like Substack,
YouTube, GitHub or custom URLs, it kind
of flattens them out over here and
groups them depending on the URL. And
it creates multiple shards. Basically
it creates a big list of URLs and splits it into
multiple pieces, which are known as shards.
And then each piece, each shard is delegated
to a new worker, right? But how that is done
is that you take that shard and this process is known
as fan out, where basically you put
each piece on a new worker. And because
maybe you don't have enough capacity between delegating
that work, that piece of work, which in our
use case is a slice of URLs, before
actually starting to process it,
you put it in a queue, right? So basically you take
this big, this huge chunk of URLs, which
can be in the order of millions, right?
You chunk it up, you split it into multiple pieces
where each piece is processed on a single worker.
But instead of directly starting to process
it, you put each piece as a future job to be
done in a queue. And then you have a limited
number of workers that take each piece from
this queue and start to process it, right?
And for example, you can have three workers
and you can have 100 slices to be processed
or you can have 10 workers and 1000 slices. So
basically they're not one-on-one, but like this,
you can have like huge spikes in your ingestion
and through this queue, you can handle all
the spikes independent on how many workers you have.
The only limitation is the speed on how you
process them. And if you want to go faster, you just add another
worker into this pool and you process them faster. So basically
this is how you take your initial input and delegate it into
multiple processes, which are known as the workers.
And each worker will basically run in this use case, this data,
this pipeline, which is pretty common
to agentic memory stuff,
right? And what this does is that it takes this.
So the same data pipeline runs on each worker,
but with different URLs, but each worker gets
basically a bunch, a list of URLs that needs
to process. And what it does, it further flattens them
out because for example, it can get as a single input,
a single URLs or RS feeds where an RS feed
can have on it, it's on its own a list
of URLs. So basically it just flattens everything
into a single list where every list points to a direct
article, let's say. Then using,
then what we need to do is basically to scrape
all that information from the internet.
And to do that, because you at this point,
right? You also have at this point a
list of URLs. And here your limitation is basically IO
operations on the internet, right? You need to basically
crawl the internet to do network operations.
And because of that, you can very easily paralyze
this operation through batch async IO, right?
You extract through a threading parallelism,
which is very good for IO operations to
like in parallel scrape a batch of links
from this window of initial URLs that
you need to process. For example,
let's say that on this worker, we need to process
1000 links, right over here, then we flatten them
out if necessary, and then we don't necessarily
want to start processing all 1000 at a single
time. But let's say that we batch them in batches
of 100, and then those 100 we can process
in parallel at a time. And this is basically the
difference. So we have initially one million documents,
we split them into multiple workers. Let's say each
worker gets 1000 URLs, and then further
in each worker, we can further split them into
batches and process them like, let's say 100
by 100. And then we can do through
async IO or process in parallel each
batch. That's basically what happens over here. And then
we can also like transform them like, I don't know, clean, for example, the
retrieve HTML if necessary, and then using a similar strategy,
we load everything as documents into our memory,
which is as well IO bounded operations,
because we need to take that document and just put
it in our database. So basically here the data
pipeline is constrained only by IO operations, network
operations, and disk operations when it comes to the
database. So basically now we have documents into the
unified agent memory. And now our goal is actually to take these documents
and transform them into knowledge graph objects, which is it
has a similar scanning strategy, but with different problems
because we need to use LLMs to process deformation and
embedding models to embed it. So let's
see how we do that. Okay,
so basically now as input into this memory
work pool, we get documents basically.
Let's say we have the same million, one million
documents that we need to process. Let's stick
to this number, right? So at the beginning from
architectural point of view, we do the same thing.
We have an orchestrator which just shards
all these, which shards these one million
documents into slice of let's say 1000
documents and fans all of this to the workers where
first it puts each slice, each shard
into the queue to be processed. And
then we have a pool of workers that take that
slice to actually process it. But now we have the
memory pipeline inside those workers that actually process
this information. And before going into the memory
pipeline, I want to highlight that all these orchestrations,
sharding, queuing, worker, all this
logic is done via prefact, right?
So prefact is the orchestrator tool that allows us to
also do the data pipelines, which weren't there
very good at, but they're also very good to
actually do like rag ingestion or memory pipelines,
basically to do rag or for agent memory or for AI
stuff where we need to move data around,
process it and load it into various storage
units. It's basically the same problem as data engineering,
but with a bit more complexity of it. Okay.
So now let's see what happens inside the memory
pipeline. So as I said, we have documents as input,
but here within a memory pipeline, we have only
a slice of the initial documents that we need to process,
right? And we go through the standard steps,
like we first chunk the content of the
documents and then we further flatten all the
chunks, right? Basically we have, let's say 1000 documents
and after we chunk them, we can have like 10,000
chunks, right? So now the numbers of units that
we need to process grows depending on how long
each document is, but let's say we have 10,000
chunks here and that's why we further need to flatten them
because it's a lot easier
to process a flat list. And now
the problem is that we don't have only a pure IO
problem, right? We need to actually, what we need
here is to extract knowledge graph triplets out
of these chunks. Basically we need to extract those
entity relationship, entity triplets for the content
of all those chunks. So basically we need an LLM to
process this information. And a very common thing
to do is here is to actually, well,
use an API such as Gemini or Claude or whatever
to basically have access to this LLM or
take an open source LLM such as one from Liquid
or QAN and host it on the VLLM server where
we have GPUs, right? These are
two common options. But
how we hook the LLM to the memory pipeline is
actually quite similar regardless of
how we host the LLM. And what we do is we
want to use batch operations, right? As I said,
similar to the IO use case, we want to batch, for example,
from these 10,000 units of
chunks, we take 100 of them and we send all those
100 to the LLM service to process at once.
And in reality is also an IO problem.
So because the actual work is done on the LLM
server that has GPUs, that that's where the actual computation
is done. Here in the memory pipeline, it can stay light and it just delegates
that information to another server. Okay.
Then we can do some, we have to do
the normalization step where we
do like, we do canonical name resolution and entity
deduplication and that type of things. And here usually
this is again very, uh, I, disk IO
bounded because here we need to query
the database to actually find similar or
similar entities. Right. So basically here we
depend on the database. So it's again,
a disk IO bounded. So again, we
can very easily paralyze it like that. And
another step is when we need to take the
content of each entity and embed it.
And this can be done in a similar fashion to how we, we did it with
the LLM, but because it's still a deep learning
model, but we can also take another spin here as an example
where we can host actually the embedding on the worker
itself. Right. Because the embedding models are lighter
and which means that we can actually run them on the CPU on the worker
itself. So we stay local, which is faster
because now we don't have like network IO
limitations at all because we are on the same
machine and we can just run again batch
operations directly on that worker. And
now as outputs, we have those knowledge
graph objects, which we load in the
database, which probably it's again,
we have this loading step, which we again
can batch and it's a disk and network
IO bounded. So yeah, basically
just to repeat, we have two levels of parallel
list here that are very important,
right? We have the, for example, for the, for the memory work
pool, we have this list of documents, 1 million documents
that we need to process. First what we do, we take that list
and shard it into slices and delegate that to workers
and each worker is basically a separate process or a separate
machine altogether. And each worker gets
like a slice, let's say 1 million, 1,000
documents and further processes it and it processes
it in parallel again by batching.
And that batching usually is IO bounded,
right? Which means you can very easily run
in parallel multiple operations
and like this, you can further as much as possible,
you can process in parallel all the elements
that are sent to particular worker. But because
in reality that's not really feasible, you batch it
again into multiple slices and you process that
in parallel. So we have two levels of slicing, the initial
level of slicing where we take it and split it into workers
and the second level of slicing where we split it
into batches. And using this architecture, depending
on your workload, you can even go crazier and here we
have like the, when we split the elements in
multiple workers, that's like pipeline parallelism
and when we further split it and parallelize it within
the pipeline, that's task parallelizing.
And at the task parallelizing level, we can
even go crazier and use like a desk or rate
cluster and actually instead of processing
it through VLM servers on the worker or
for example if we have like very hardcore
embedding type of things to do and we don't want to
run an embedding model on a VLM server, we can
further take all of that and run it on the rate cluster
or desk cluster to actually parallelize it even further
and run the whole batch at once in parallel
for real on another cluster of GPUs.
So you can get creative here as long as you properly
divide these elements into the architecture.
[ Silence ]